Come eat this
와서 이거 먹어
That's enough...you need to eat more too.
그 정도면 됐어......너도 더 먹어야 해
Madam, what happened to Mr. Fahrenheit?
부인, 화씨에게 무슨 일이 생겼어요
I ate it a bit hastily.
좀 급하게 먹었어요
Please excuse me first.
먼저 실례하겠습니다.
Why did you just leave?
왜 방금 떠나셨나요?
are you okay… you eat
괜찮아…너희는 먹어라
Watch here
여기에서 시청하세요
What happened?
어떻게 됐나요?
-Yeah -It’s okay‥
-응 -괜찮아‥
Now it's time to eat, time to drink
이제 밥 먹을 시간, 마실 시간이야
another bottle of wine
또 다른 와인병
Let's eat ours
우리꺼 먹자
What happened to my brother?
내 동생에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Fahrenheit is now......
화씨는 지금 ......
In Mu Xiaoniang’s room
무샤오니앙의 방에서
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻인가요?
I don't even know the species
종도 모르지
I just heard someone report it.
방금 누군가가 신고하는 것을 들었습니다.
Mr. Hua said that he broke into Mu Xiaoniang’s room.
Hua 씨가 Mu Xiaoniang의 방에 침입했다고 말했습니다.
brother… wake up
형… 일어나
Go see Muyao
무야오 보러가기
brother ‥
형 ‥
little daughter
작은 딸
wake up
깨우다
brother
형
younger sister
여동생
blood
피
What happen?
무슨 일이에요?
Ouch
아야오
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
uncle
삼촌
I'm doing great
잘 지내요
Fortunately, the perilla seeds arrived just in time.
다행히 들깨가 딱 맞춰 도착했어요.
just now‥
방금‥
I just missed you
방금 보고 싶었어
It looks like Mr. Hwa is injured.
화 씨가 부상을 입은 것 같습니다.
uncle‥
삼촌‥
Calm down and listen to me first.
진정하고 내 말을 먼저 들어보세요
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
Madam, are you okay?
부인, 괜찮으세요?
I look at my hands.
나는 내 손을 본다.
bleeding
출혈
-Hua Rongzhou -Uncle
-화룽저우 (Hua Rongzhou ) -삼촌
Get out of the way, uncle, listen to me.
비켜주세요, 삼촌, 내 말 좀 들어보세요
Just calm down. The situation is unclear right now.
일단 진정하세요 지금은 상황이 불분명해요
I am afraid that there is no room for impulsive movement.
충동적으로 움직일 여지가 없을까 두렵습니다
Get out of the way
비켜서 다
Uncle, I can't kill him now.
삼촌, 이제 그 사람을 죽일 수는 없어요
Let's first investigate the cause of the problem
먼저 문제의 원인을 조사해보자
It's not too late to punish
처벌하기엔 아직 늦지 않았다
Find out why?
이유를 알아보세요?
How is your personality?
형 성격은 어때요?
Don’t you even know it yourself?
스스로도 모르시나요?
Let me tell you why I have good intentions
왜 좋은 의도를 가지고 있는지 말해줄게
Go and ask the big princess for ayao.
가서 큰 공주에게 아야오를 물어보세요
Now it seems
이제는 것 같다
It's just that you, brothers and sisters, have already made plans together.
단지 형제자매 여러분이 이미 함께 계획을 세웠을 뿐입니다.
I know I have fooled you many times before.
나는 내가 전에도 여러 번 당신을 속였다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
No wonder my uncle doesn't trust me anymore
삼촌이 더 이상 나를 믿지 않는 것도 당연합니다
But one thing comes together
하지만 한 가지는 하나로 다가온다
-Uncle, calm down . -You don't have to kill him.
-삼촌, 진정하세요 -그 사람을 죽일 필요는 없어요
But you have to destroy both his arms
하지만 그의 두 팔을 모두 파괴해야 해
Please let me know who I shouldn't touch.
만지면 안 되는 사람이 누구인지 알려주세요.
younger sister‥
여동생‥
Save me, sister
구해줘 언니
Sister, please save me
언니, 살려주세요
younger sister
여동생
It's not in the way, right?
방해가 되지 않는 거죠?
younger sister‥
여동생‥
Brother, I think you'd better calm down.
형님, 진정하시는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
how?
어떻게?
Brother, this look
형님, 이 표정
Could it be that you want to fight with me?
혹시 나랑 싸우고 싶은 건 아닐까?
What does owner mean?
주인은 무슨 뜻인가요?
Are you going to defend that loser?
당신은 그 패자를 옹호할 건가요?
Huashen is Huadu Guan's only son.
Huashen은 Huadu Guan의 외아들입니다.
Brother, I understand how you feel.
형님 심정 이해해요
But it's better not to lose heart
하지만 마음을 잃지 않는 것이 좋습니다
He dared to be rude to my girl today.
그 사람이 오늘 감히 내 여자에게 무례하게 굴었어
Could it be that his identity has become his protective umbrella?
그의 정체성이 그의 보호우산이 된 것은 아닐까?
I'm not trying to protect that person.
나는 그 사람을 보호하려는 것이 아니다.
In my opinion
내 생각에는
Better to put him in jail first.
그 사람을 먼저 감옥에 가두는 게 낫지
Please wait until Magistrate Wang Hyeon finds out clearly and finds you guilty of the crime.
왕현 치안판사가 앞으로 명확하게 알아낸 후 귀하에게 범죄에 대해 유죄를 선고할 때까지 기다리십시오.
I have more important things to do today
오늘은 더 중요한 일이 있어
A senior is watching
선배가 지켜보고 있다
Magistrate Wang County did not dare to indulge Hua Shen.
왕 현 치안판사는 감히 화셴(Hua Shen)을 탐닉하지 않았습니다.
it's easier for him
그에게는 더 쉽습니다
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Where are you taking me?
나를 어디로 데려가나요?
Sister, please save me, sister
언니, 살려주세요, 언니
Thank you, Master.
감사합니다, 스승님
Now you return to the yard to treat your wounds.
이제 당신은 상처를 치료하기 위해 마당으로 돌아갑니다.
- But there are a lot of people in the front yard. - I will take care of the front yard.
- 그런데 앞마당에는 사람이 많아요. - 앞마당은 제가 처리하겠습니다.
You can go back safely.
안심하고 돌아가시면 됩니다
farewell to the head of the household
가장에게 작별 인사
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
I'm doing great
잘 지내요
sorry
죄송합니다
I'm sorry ma'am
미안해요 부인
What do you mean you're sorry?
무슨 미안하다는 말이야?
Very good job
아주 잘했어요
I should be thankful
감사해야겠어요
Hearing your voice, I still have some strength left.
목소리를 들으니 아직 힘이 좀 남아있네요.
I feel at ease now
이제 마음이 편해졌어요
Don't forget to ask your doctor to prescribe a good medicine for you later
나중에 의사에게 좋은 약을 처방해 달라고 요청하는 것을 잊지 마세요
attentive
주의 깊은
come
오다
send this to her
그녀에게 이것을 보내세요
Please bear with me, ma’am.
참아주세요, 부인.
It hurts so much
너무 아파요
Be patient
참아라
It'll be okay soon
곧 괜찮아질 거예요
The slave met his master
노예가 주인을 만났어요
-Lyrics‥ - I will do it.
-가사부‥ - 내가 할게요
Teacher, what are you doing?
선생님, 뭐 하시는 거예요?
Do not worry. Guests are placed in the front yard.
걱정하지 마십시오. 앞마당에 손님이 배치되어 있습니다.
Everyone is leaving
모두 떠나고 있어
House owner
집주인
Let's do it to the ginkgo tree
은행나무에게 시키자
Don’t you trust my medical skills?
내 의료 기술을 믿지 못하시나요?
no
아니요
I just think it's against etiquette.
그냥 예의에 어긋나는 것 같아요
Master, why don't you knock me out and treat my wounds?
스승님, 저를 기절시키고 상처를 치료해주시는 게 어때요?
'Cause you're so afraid of pain
넌 고통을 너무 두려워하니까
Why are you standing in front of Hua Shen?
Hua Shen 앞에 서 있는 이유는 무엇입니까?
That person is my brother after all
그 사람은 결국 내 동생이야
Why are you so fast? I just…
왜 이렇게 빨라요 난 그냥…
I'll put this aside for now.
당분간은 이 문제를 내려 놓겠습니다.
but you need to know
하지만 당신은 알아야 해요
In the end, you have to give the answer.
결국 선배님이 답을 주셔야 해요.
My uncle was so angry.
삼촌이 너무 화났어
Isn't the head of the household angry?
가장이 화가 난 것은 아닌가?
Why should I be angry?
왜 화를 내야 합니까?
Why did my landlord help me?
집주인은 왜 나를 도와줬나요?
Didn't you test me every day before?
예전에는 나를 매일 시험하지 않았나요?
Because you helped me protect mine...
당신이 내 것을 지키는 데 도움을 주었으니까 ‥
secret of my heart
내 마음의 비밀
Then we can be considered people in the same boat.
그러면 우리는 같은 배를 탄 사람들 로 간주될 수 있습니다 .
how boring he is
그 사람은 얼마나 지루한가
If you like someone else, should you find someone to share it with?
다른 사람이 마음에 들면 그것을 공유할 사람을 찾아야 합니까?
Okay, I'll go first.
알았어, 나 먼저 갈게
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Now when I told the doctor to get me some medicine
지금 내가 의사에게 약을 사오라고 했을 때
When he saw guard Hua taking a bottle of trauma medicine, he hurriedly ran out.
경비병 후아가 외상약 한 병을 복용하는 것을 본 그는 서둘러 뛰쳐나갔다.
He didn't even hear me greet him.
그는 내가 그에게 인사하는 것을 듣지도 못했습니다.
I don't know how serious his injuries are.
나는 그의 부상이 얼마나 심각한지 모른다.
When I just got back
지금 막 돌아왔을 때
I saw that person at the door too
나도 문 앞에서 그 사람 봤어
Was Hualongzhou also injured?
화룽저우도 부상을 입었나요?
I do not know either
나도 잘 모르겠어
I didn't look closely right now.
지금은 자세히 안 봤는데
he fell on a chair
그는 의자에 넘어졌다
It looks like it has some scratches.
흠집이 좀 있는 것 같아요.
green bamboo
녹색 대나무
Why don't you go to Hua Rongzhou and check it out for me?
나 대신 Hua Rongzhou에 가서 확인해 보는 게 어때?
What is happening to this girl?
이 소녀에게 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
If you get a chance on a weekday
평일에 기회가 된다면
Isn’t everyone so happy that they want to go to heaven?
다들 너무 기뻐서 천국 가고 싶어하지 않나요?
Why aren't you happy today?
오늘은 왜 행복하지 않나요?
Could it be because he was worried about the guard, Fahrenheit?
경비병 화씨가 걱정되어서 그런 건 아닐까?
Why don't you put the medicine away first?
먼저 약을 치워두는 게 어때요?
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
do you feel
당신은 느끼나요
Do you feel like your landlord is treating you differently?
집 주인이 당신을 다르게 대하는 것 같나요?
It's definitely different
그건 확실히 다른데
So, madam, what are you going to do?
그럼 부인, 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
you don't understand
당신은 이해하지 않는다
The landlord is just like that.
집주인은 그냥 그렇거든요
I know his secret.
나는 그의 비밀을 알고 있다
So you look at me differently
그래서 당신은 나를 다르게 보는 거죠
secret?
비밀?
What does eldest ajumma mean?
큰아줌마은 무슨 뜻인가요?
They say it's a secret
비밀이라고 하던데
Why are you still asking?
왜 아직도 물어보시나요?
Qian Er
치엔얼
What did your uncle say?
삼촌이 뭐라고 했어?
I haven't had time to see my uncle yet.
아직 삼촌을 볼 시간이 없었어요
I asked your father last night
내가 어젯밤에 네 아버지한테 물었지
The person who asked his uncle to send him to Yamen
삼촌에게 야멘으로 보내달라고 부탁했다는 사람
That's why...
그 때문이군요 ......
Such a shameful thing
그런 치욕스러운 일이
Your father is afraid of this problem becoming bigger.
네 아버지는 이 문제가 더 커지는 것을 두려워하신다.
So I don't dare step forward and protect you.
그래서 난 감히 나서서 당신을 보호하지 못해요
We just have to ask more questions.
더 많은 질문을 드려야 할 뿐입니다.
i know it well
나는 그것을 잘 알고 있다
What good is it to know what you know?
당신이 아는 것을 아는 것이 무슨 소용이 있습니까?
Your brother grew up eating good clothes and good food.
네 동생은 좋은 옷과 좋은 음식을 먹고 자랐어
How can he survive in prison?
그는 어떻게 감옥에서 살 수 있습니까?
He's never experienced pain like that
그 사람은 그런 고통을 겪어본 적이 없어
I won't sit still
나는 가만히 앉아 있지 않을 것이다
But first we need to get to the bottom of this problem.
하지만 먼저 이 문제의 진상을 알아볼 필요가 있습니다.
Only then can I explain.
그래야만 설명을 할 수 있어요
Yesterday when your brother was taken away
어제 네 동생이 끌려갔을 때
i'm not here
난 여기 없어
Why don't you quit?
그만 두는 게 어때?
He is your only biological brother
그는 당신의 유일한 생물학적 형제입니다
I remember when you were still in my belly
네가 아직 내 뱃속에 있었을 때를 기억해
That person touches my stomach every day and says
그 사람은 매일 내 배를 만지며 말해요
Come out quickly...
빨리 나와라 ‥
Brother protect me
형이 지켜줘
Now something big has happened to your brother
이제 네 동생에게 큰 일이 일어났어
Can you sit here steadily?
여기 착실히 앉아 계실 수 있나요?
Mom, don't worry
엄마, 걱정하지 마세요
If my younger brother was really treated unfairly
만약 내 동생이 정말 억울한 일을 당했다면
I will never stay still.
나는 결코 가만히 있지 않을 것이다
Then you didn't go to jail to ask questions.
그러면 당신은 질문하러 감옥에 가지 않았습니다.
Who on earth did wrong to your brother?
도대체 누가 네 동생에게 잘못을 하였느냐?
i went
나는 갔다
I found Magistrate Wang Hyeon.
왕현 치안판사를 찾았어요
He won't let me in
그 사람은 날 들여보내지 않을 거야
They said it would take a few days to watch.
지켜보는 데 며칠이 걸릴 거라고 하더군요
within a few days
며칠 안에
i miss myself deeply
나는 나를 깊이 그리워한다
I can't spend a day in jail
감옥에서 하루도 보낼 수 없어
How could he live there?
그는 어떻게 거기에서 살 수 있었습니까?
Anyway, it's up to you‥
어쨌든, 이 문제는 당신에게 달려있습니다 ‥
This is what happened here with you.
너랑 여기서 일어난 일이야
You are my uncle's eldest wife.
당신은 내 삼촌의 큰 부인이에요
you go and find him
너는 가서 그를 찾아라
I don't believe he won't let you in
나는 그가 당신을 들여 보내지 않을 것이라고 믿지 않습니다
My brother was just arrested.
내 동생이 방금 체포됐어요
Now I don't even know what happened yesterday.
이제 나는 어제 무슨 일이 일어났는지조차 모릅니다 .
What good is going to jail now?
지금 감옥에 가도 무슨 소용이 있나요?
-What can you do? -So what can you do here?
-무엇을 할 수 있나요? -그럼 여기서 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
i know
알아요
You always hated your brother because he was the one who insulted you.
당신은 당신을 모욕하는 사람이라는 이유로 항상 당신의 형제를 싫어했습니다.
It's not you who's in jail now.
지금 감옥에 있는 건 당신이 아니에요
It's not you who suffers.
고통받는 것은 당신이 아니다
Of course, don't rush.
물론 서두르지 마세요.
I think my brother would be embarrassed
형이 부끄러워할 것 같아
Or are you embarrassed by your own bad behavior?
아니면 자신의 나쁜 행실 때문에 당황하고 있습니까?
I have never been to jail.
나는 감옥에 가본 적이 없다.
But what good is worrying now?
하지만 지금 걱정해도 무슨 소용이 있나요?
Make a fuss before the problem is resolved
문제가 해결되기도 전에 소란을 피우다
It just makes people grab the handle.
사람들이 손잡이를 잡게 만들 뿐이죠
And how did Mom know this?
그리고 엄마는 이걸 어떻게 알았지?
Is it my brother's fault?
내 동생 탓인가?
Mom is coming home from today
엄마가 오늘부터 들어오세요
keep talking
계속 말해봐
I'm worried that my brother will have a hard time in prison.
형이 감옥에서 힘든 시간을 보낼까 봐 걱정된다.
Did your mom ask?
엄마가 물어봤어?
Why is your hand bandaged?
손에 붕대를 감은 이유는 무엇입니까?
-Me‥ - Forget it, mom was always biased.
-나‥ - 잊어버려라, 엄마는 늘 편파적이셨다.
i am used to it
나는 그것에 익숙하다
If mom doesn't give you a satisfactory answer today,
오늘 엄마가 만족스러운 대답을 하지 못한다면
I'm afraid you won't be able to let me go easily
네가 나를 쉽게 놓지 못할까봐 두려워
Now go to jail
자, 이제 감옥에 가세요
Ask more clearly
좀 더 명확하게 물어보세요
Who framed your brother?
누가 당신 동생을 모함했나요?
ma'am
부인
What I just said was a bit heartbreaking.
방금 내가 한 말은 좀 마음이 아팠다.
If you care, you will become confused and no longer in control.
신경쓰면 혼란에 빠지고 더 이상 통제할 수 없게 됩니다.
Rescue Shen'er first
먼저 쉔어를 구출하세요
arrive
도착하다
younger sister‥
여동생‥
Sister, why are you here?
언니, 여기 왜 왔나요?
I was trapped for a day and a night
하루 밤낮을 갇혀 있었어
Brother, haven’t you figured out the situation yet?
형님, 아직 상황파악 못하셨나요?
I just came in really hard.
방금 엄청 힘들게 들어왔어
Mom is still blocked from the outside world.
엄마는 지금도 외부에서 차단되어 있어요
So are you here to take me away?
그럼 나를 데리고 나가려고 여기 온 거야?
huh?
응?
Brother, you are thinking too simply.
형제여, 당신은 너무 단순하게 생각하고 있습니다.
How many times have I said this?
내가 몇 번이나 말했지?
Mu Yao is not someone you can touch.
무야오는 만질 수 있는 사람이 아니다
Why don't you have a long memory?
왜 기억력이 길지 않니?
What my sister said
언니가 한 말
i keep that in mind
나는 그것을 명심한다
The person you spoke to cannot move
당신이 말한 사람은 움직일 수 없습니다
Even if you die, you won't dare change your mind.
죽어도 감히 마음을 바꾸지 못합니다.
Why doesn't my sister believe me?
언니는 왜 내 말을 믿지 않는 걸까요?
So what happened yesterday?
그럼 어제 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Why did you show up in Mu Yao’s room looking disheveled?
왜 무야오의 방에 흐트러진 모습으로 나타났나요?
Me, I don’t know either.
나、나도 모르겠어
I drank too much yesterday
어제 술을 너무 많이 마셨어
Waking up in the backyard
뒷마당에서 정신을 차리고
My sister's housekeeper also sent me a message telling me to be patient.
내 여동생의 가정부도 나에게 인내심을 가지라는 메시지를 보냈습니다 .
don't move
움직이지 마세요
I was always in that pavilion
나는 항상 그 파빌리온에 있었어요
Don't you dare move
감히 움직이지 마세요
And after that?
그리고 그 후에?
Later......I
나중에......나
I think my brother would like to stay here a few more days.
내 동생은 여기에 며칠 더 머물고 싶어하는 것 같습니다.
I said...
나는 말했다‥
I saw it later in the backyard.
나중에 뒷뜰에서 보니
I saw a servant girl who gave birth to a good child.
나는 좋은 아이를 낳은 여종을 보았다
She rejected me and welcomed me
그녀는 나를 거절하고 환영해주기도 했어
I was drunk and chased her around.
나는 술에 취해 그녀를 쫓아다녔다.
As a result, I just entered the courtyard.
그 결과 나는 방금 안뜰로 들어갔습니다.
he lost consciousness
그는 의식을 잃었다
When I woke up, I saw you, my sister, appearing before me.
내가 잠에서 깨어났을 때, 내 앞에 나타난 당신, 내 여동생을 보았습니다.
I was so scared that I didn't dare say anything.
너무 무서워서 감히 아무 말도 할 수 없었습니다.
me‥
나‥
Are you sure that the maid took the initiative to seduce you?
하녀가 주도적으로 당신을 유혹했다고 확신하나요?
That person keeps spying on me
그 사람이 계속 나를 훔쳐보는데
Aren’t you just interested in me?
그냥 나한테 관심 있는 거 아니야?
When people see you, they are interested in you.
사람들이 당신을 볼 때 당신에게 관심이 있습니다.
I drank too much and my lewd nature came out.
술을 너무 많이 마셔서 음란한 본성이 드러났어요
Are you still making excuses?
지금도 변명하고 있나요?
Who can care about themselves when they're drunk?
술에 취해 누가 자기 자신을 걱정할 수 있겠습니까?
Maybe I drank too much and my eyesight was bad.
어쩌면 내가 너무 많이 마셔서 시력이 나빠졌을 수도 있다.
not seeing clearly
명확하게 보지 못함
So I thought other people were interested in me.
그래서 다른 사람들이 나에게 관심이 있는 줄 착각했어요.
This time, I accidentally broke into someone else's yard and was treated like a villain.
이번에는 실수로 남의 집 마당에 침입해서 악당 취급을 받았습니다.
Sister, it's not my fault
언니, 내 잘못이 아니에요
I think he's very confident in what he says.
내 생각엔 형이 자기 말에 아주 자신감이 있는 것 같아.
There is no trace of sadness in my mother's words.
어머니의 말에는 슬픔의 기미가 없다
That's right, but
그렇긴 한데
Brother, please stay here for a few more days.
형님, 며칠만 더 여기 계세요.
-Save your memories -Sister‥
-기억을 살려라 -언니‥
Sister, please save me
언니, 살려주세요
It's dirty and smelly in here.
여기 더럽고 냄새나는데
and rat
그리고 쥐
The guards here also tortured me.
여기 간수들도 나를 고문했어요
I don't think you'll survive after a few days, sister.
며칠 뒤에는 살아남지 못할 것 같아요, 언니.
-Sister -Really?
-언니 -정말요?
I saw a wound on my brother's head
나는 내 동생의 머리에 상처를 보았다
Good bandage.
붕대를 잘 감았어
Where else were you abused by the guards?
또 어디에서 간수들에게 학대를 받았습니까?
-I... -Just stay here and remember me for a long time.
-나‥ -그냥 여기 있으면서 오래오래 기억해줘
younger sister‥
여동생‥
sisters
자매
younger sister
여동생
How is your brother?
니 동생 잘 지내?
How many times have I said Shen'er?
내가 Shen'er라고 몇 번이나 말했습니까?
He can't change his lewd habits
그 사람은 그 음란한 습관을 바꿀 수 없어
This time...
이 시간‥
This time at your house
이번에도 네 집에서
Something big happened
이런 큰 일이 일어났어요
I really think I need to hit him.
정말 한 대 때려줘야 할 것 같아요.
My mom thinks so too...
우리 엄마도 그렇게 생각해 ‥
Was it your fault this time?
이번에는 형 잘못이었나?
Qian Er
치엔얼
Brother‥
동생‥
Your brother is a bit lewd.
네 동생은 좀 음탕한 편이야
But this time...
그런데 이번에는 ......
Isn't it his fault that he drank too much?
술을 너무 많이 먹은 것도 그의 잘못이 아닌가?
our hua family
우리 후아 가족
But he is an only son
하지만 그 사람은 외아들이에요
He's your only brother too
그 사람도 너의 하나뿐인 형제야
You're just mad at your mom.
넌 그냥 엄마한테 화났을 뿐이야
You can't ignore me too
형도 무시하면 안 돼
children
어린이
How can you be angry?
어떻게 화를 낼 수 있나요?
just a feeling
그냥 느낌
It's not my sister's fault this time
이번에는 내 동생 잘못이 아니야
right?
오른쪽?
Slave saw big wife
노예는 큰 부인을 보았다
You're mine, there's no need for courtesy
넌 나만의 것 예의가 필요 없어
I called here to ask a few questions.
몇 가지 질문을 하려고 여기로 전화했어요.
Yesterday I asked you to find my sister
어제 내가 내 동생을 찾아달라고 부탁했어요
Is there anything unusual about that person?
그 사람 주변에 특이한 점이 있나요?
When the slave went into the backyard to look for Fahrenheit,
노예가 화씨를 찾으러 뒷마당에 갔을 때,
He sits alone in the pavilion
그는 정자에 혼자 앉아 있다
People around me said they were looking for hangover soup.
주변 사람들이 해장국을 찾고 있다고 하더군요.
What did he say after you finished preaching?
당신이 설교를 마친 후에 그는 무엇이라고 말했습니까?
Mr. Fah said he drank too much wine today.
화씨가 오늘 와인을 너무 많이 마셨다고 하더군요
I want to stay in the pavilion forever
나는 영원히 파빌리온에 머물고 싶다
He even asked his slave to inform Madam Hua.
그는 심지어 그의 노예에게 Hua 부인에게 알리라고 요청했습니다.
He said he would look for him in the pavilion after the event.
그는 행사가 끝난 후 정자에서 그를 찾아보겠다고 말했다.
Then did you tell anyone?
그럼 누구한테라도 말했어?
Is Huashen in the backyard pavilion?
Huashen이 뒷마당 정자에 있나요?
no
아니요
Then on the way back
그럼 돌아오는 길에
Have you met anyone else?
다른 사람을 만났나요?
nor
...도 아니다
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Did the slave do something wrong?
노예가 뭔가 잘못한 걸까요?
It has nothing to do with you.
너랑은 아무 상관 없어
Don't think too much, go back and rest first.
너무 생각하지 말고 먼저 돌아가서 쉬어
Madam, what happened to Cui Zhou?
부인, 추이주에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
It's okay, just ask
괜찮아 그냥 물어봐
Just take it easy.
그냥 편하게 지내세요.
Which yard is Mu Yao in now?
무야오는 지금 어느 마당에 있나요?
It's still my old residence.
아직 예전 거주지인데
I just got refurbished
방금 단장했어요
good
좋은
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
The day before yesterday, my uncle was angry.
그저께 삼촌이 화를 내셨어요
It's neither easy nor heavy.
쉽지도 무겁지도 않습니다.
Injuries should also not be minor.
부상도 경미해서는 안됩니다.
There is no need to stay here any longer.
더 이상 여기에 머물 필요가 없습니다.
First, let's go home and rest.
우선 집으로 돌아가서 쉬자.
my men are fine
내 부하들은 괜찮다
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
It was my uncle who asked me to look at Mu Xiaoniang’s yard.
Mu Xiaoniang의 마당을 보라고 한 사람은 삼촌이었습니다.
They said they shouldn't let anyone in without permission.
아무나 함부로 들여보내면 안 된다고 하더군요.
you‥
너‥
Go tell Mu Yao
무야오한테 가서 말해
she would be willing to see me
그녀는 나를 기꺼이 볼 것입니다
Madam, please
부인, 부탁해요
You're guarding me outside.
밖에서 지키고 계시네요
yes
예
Have you been waiting for me for a long time?
오랫동안 나를 기다리고 있었나요?
When you come to defend Hua Shen
Hua Shen을 변호하러 오면
Should we lower our stance?
입장을 낮춰야 할까요?
my brother didn't do anything wrong
내 동생은 아무 잘못도 하지 않았어
Why should I advocate for him?
내가 왜 그를 위해 변호해야 합니까?
It's just the two of us here now
지금 여기엔 우리 둘뿐이야
Then I will speak openly and directly.
그러면 공개적이고 직접적으로 말하겠습니다.
I thought about it
나는 생각했다
Have you ever experienced being trapped?
갇힌 경험을 하신 적이 있나요?
So I won't use this method in the future.
그래서 앞으로는 이 방법을 사용하지 않겠습니다.
Now I guess I was wrong
이제 내 생각이 틀린 것 같아
I'm so disappointed in you.
너 정말 실망스럽다
Originally, I didn’t want to come today.
원래 오늘은 오기 싫었는데
But you put so much effort into designing it.
그런데 너무 공들여 디자인하셨네요
I would be happy to cooperate with you
나는 당신과 협력하는 것이 좋을 것입니다
Don't let all your efforts go in vain
여러분의 모든 노력이 헛되지 않도록
I said it once
내가 한 번 말했었지
I won't argue with you anymore
나는 더 이상 당신과 논쟁하지 않을 것입니다
But you still don't believe it
하지만 넌 아직도 믿지 않지
at last
결국
Why do we have to use these vulgar methods?
왜 이런 저속한 수법을 사용해야 합니까?
Use Jong Yeran for me.
나에게 종예란을 이용하라
Do you think I'm doing it for him?
내가 그 사람을 위해서 그런 짓을 하고 있다고 생각하세요?
If not, what else is it for?
그렇지 않다면 그것은 또 무엇을 위한 것인가?
Since taking steps to design Huashen
Huashen을 디자인하기 위해 조치를 취한 이후로
Then I won't turn a blind eye to it.
그럼 눈감아주지 않을게
Every injustice has its owner, and every debt has its owner.
모든 불의에는 주인이 있고, 모든 빚에는 주인이 있습니다.
Even before
이전에도
I tolerate you everywhere because I feel guilty about you
나는 당신에 대해 죄책감을 느끼기 때문에 어디에서나 당신을 용납합니다
But now you use the means
하지만 이제 당신은 수단을 사용합니다
Involve innocent people around me
내 주변의 무고한 사람들을 연루시키세요
I won't show you any more mercy
더 이상 자비를 베풀지 않겠습니다
Every injustice has its owner, and every debt has its owner.
모든 불의에는 주인이 있고, 모든 빚에는 주인이 있습니다.
Huaqian
화첸
How did you have the courage to say this to me?
어떻게 나에게 이런 말을 할 용기가 있었나요?
Why can't I?
나는 왜 할 수 없습니까?
uncle
삼촌
Magistrate Wang Xuan sent more people here.
왕 현 치안판사는 더 많은 사람들을 이곳으로 보냈습니다.
It's about the Huashen incident.
Huashen 사건에 관한 것입니다.
I also want to ask Mu Xiaoniang something.
저도 Mu Xiaoniang에게 물어보고 싶은 게 있어요.
Should I make them wait this time?
이번에는 그들을 기다리게 해야 하나요?
wait
기다리다
yes
예
etc.
등.
I'll ask first
내가 먼저 물어볼게
Fahrenheit people
화씨네 사람들아
After all, they are all selfish and cannot distinguish between right and wrong.
역시 그들은 모두 이기적이고 옳고 그름을 구별하지 못하는 사람들이다.
You said Huashen was right.
당신은 Huashen이 옳았다고 말했어요
Weren't you the one who planned the wedding feast?
혼인 잔치를 계획한 사람이 당신이 아니었나요?
My younger brother is a promiscuous man
내 동생은 문란한 남자지만
But I don't have any bad intentions towards you
하지만 난 당신을 향한 어떤 나쁜 의도도 없어요
huh?
응?
i don't know anything else
나는 다른 것을 모른다
But my brother won't lie to me
하지만 내 동생은 내 앞에서 거짓말을 하지 않을 거야
Because I warned him many times
내가 그에게 여러 번 경고했기 때문에
He will never go against my will
그 사람은 결코 내 뜻에 어긋나지 않을 거야
Not to mention the past...
과거는 말할 ​​것도 없고 ......
Besides, I've known you before
게다가 난 당신을 전부터 알고 있었어요
you are not that kind
당신은 그런 종류가 아니다
A person who sheds tears when something happens
무슨 일이 생기면 눈물을 흘리는 사람
That day, you pretended to be scared and hid in a corner.
그날 너는 겁먹은 척 구석에 숨어버렸지
You're actually acting, right?
당신은 실제로 연기하고 있는 거죠, 그렇죠?
The purpose is obvious
목적은 뻔해
yes
예
What happened that day was what I had planned.
그날 일어난 일은 내가 계획한 일이었어
Huashen really didn't have any ill will towards me.
Huashen은 정말로 나에 대한 어떤 악의도 갖고 있지 않았습니다.
A few days ago, I heard that a female servant had died in that mansion.
며칠 전 그 저택에서 여종 하나가 죽었다는 소식을 들었습니다.
However, I met Mr. Fahrenheit at the wedding reception.
그런데 결혼식 피로연에서 화씨를 만나다
Why weren't you hurt at all?
왜 전혀 다치지 않았나요?
Painters have the protective umbrella of the painter.
화가에는 화도관의 보호우산이 있습니다
The fate of a simple female envoy
단순한 여성 사절의 운명
Of course I can't take my eyes off it at all
당연하지 난 전혀 눈을 못 떼지
What do you want to say?
말하고 싶은게 뭡니까?
The special envoy committed suicide that day.
그날 자살한 특사
It's Linglong.
링롱이에요
These were all purchased under the director's instructions.
모두 감독님의 지시로 구입한 것들입니다.
The girl is old enough to discuss marriage.
그 소녀는 결혼을 논의할 나이가 되었습니다.
Now it's time to get dressed.
이제 옷을 입을 시간이에요
look at these gems
이 보석들을 보세요
It's really beautiful
정말 아름다워
do you like it?
당신은 그것을 좋아합니까?
it's up to you
그건 당신에게 달렸습니다
i am a slave
나는 노예입니다
How can you wear such expensive clothes?
어떻게 그렇게 비싼 옷을 입을 수 있지?
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
this
이것
It is recommended not to wear it.
입지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Wear it
입으세요
wonderful
멋진
Didn't I say I was old enough to talk about marriage?
내가 결혼을 논할 나이가 됐다고 하지 않았나요?
But you are a year older than me
그래도 넌 나보다 한 살 더 많아
This is my dowry for you
이건 당신을 위한 내 지참금이에요
dowry?
결혼 지참금?
you ah you
너 아 너
What nonsense are you talking about?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하는거야?
Do not run
뛰지 마세요
Linglong lost his parents at a young age.
Linglong은 어렸을 때부터 부모를 잃었습니다.
Grew up in the North with me.
나와 함께 북쪽에서 자랐어요
You still have to remember her, right?
아직도 그녀를 기억해야겠죠?
there are some good ones
좋은 것들이 있습니다
Come and try it
와서 해보세요
You were originally convicted and sold.
당신은 원래 유죄 판결을 받고 팔렸습니다.
I'm just an orphan
고아일 뿐이야
no family
가족 없음
At that time, my father was falsely accused and exiled.
그땐 아버지가 누명을 쓰고 유배됐는데
All the slaves of our shepherd's family were sold.
우리 목자 가족의 노예가 모두 팔렸습니다.
Since they are slaves, they are the same no matter where they are sold.
그들은 노예이므로 어디에 팔아도 똑같습니다.
I was originally thinking of doing that too.
나도 원래 그럴 생각이었는데
but
하지만
Why did Huashen buy her?
왜 Huashen이 그녀를 샀나요?
About you?
당신에 대한?
- I will beat you to death ‥ - Hwahyeong ‥
- 때려죽이겠어 ‥ - 화형님 ‥
Don't fight...
싸우지 마‥
This looks so painful.
이거 너무 괴로워 보이는데, 이거.
ungrateful
배은망덕한 것
my friend likes you
내 친구가 당신을 좋아해요
That's your blessing, you know?
그게 네 축복이야, 알지?
If you don't want to do it, forget it.
하기 싫으면 잊어버리세요
Still hitting my rhubarb
아직도 내 대황을 때리잖아
Who gave you courage?
누가 당신에게 용기를 주었나요?
I know I was wrong too
나도 내가 틀렸다는 걸 알아
Darangjun, calm down.
다랑준 진정해
concubine?
첩?
What kind of concubine are you?
당신은 어떤 종류의 첩입니까?
You're just a cheap maid
넌 그냥 싸구려 하녀일 뿐이야
You are the lowly slave I bought you.
너는 내가 사준 비천한 노예야
Still feeling bad?
아직도 기분이 안 좋나요?
Hwahyeong…
화형님…
As an adult, I don't remember the villain's mistakes.
어른인 나는 악당의 잘못을 기억하지 못한다.
please save me
당신을 살려주세요
You should immediately pack your bags and go back with Brother Wang.
당신은 즉시 짐을 싸서 왕 형제님과 함께 돌아가십시오.
Did you hear that?
그거 들었어?
Oro-gun
오로 군
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
What he means is
그가 의미하는 바는
you are already mine
당신은 이미 내 것입니다
that
그건
Oro-gun
오로 군
One woman doesn't care about two husbands
한 여자는 두 남편을 걱정하지 않습니다
How could you give up on me?
어떻게 나를 포기할 수 있니?
Did I give you a face?
내가 당신에게 얼굴을 주었나요?
You're just a cheap maid
넌 그냥 싸구려 하녀일 뿐이야
I will give it to anyone who says I will give it to you.
내가 네게 주겠다고 말하는 사람에게는 그것을 주겠다.
Beauty, rest assured
아름다움, 안심하세요
Our house is not worse than Brother Hua's house
우리 집은 화 형제 집보다 나쁘지 않습니다.
i will love you well
나는 당신을 잘 사랑할 것입니다
It's okay if you don't want to go.
가고 싶지 않아도 괜찮습니다.
I'm telling you, you won't go
내가 말하는데, 넌 가지 않을 거야
Tomorrow I will sell you to a whorehouse.
내일 내가 너를 창녀집에 팔아버릴 것이다
Check if you are listening or not
듣는지 안 듣는지 확인하세요
walk
걷다
Even though I am a slave
나는 노예인데도
I can't stand such humiliation
나는 그런 굴욕을 참을 수 없다
Little daughter...
작은 딸‥
little daughter
작은 딸
so
그래서
Huaqian
화첸
Where did you get your confidence?
어디서 자신감을 얻었나요?
Do you dare to say that Hua Shen is innocent in front of me?
내 앞에서 Hua Shen이 무죄라고 감히 말할 수 있습니까?
That lowly maid who died in your mansion
당신의 저택에서 죽은 그 비천한 하녀
Someone who is like a sister to me
나에게 언니 같은 사람
-Me... -What's wrong?
-나‥ -왜 그래?
What else do you want to say?
또 무슨 말을 하고 싶나요?
Huaqian
화첸
I gave you time, I gave you a chance
난 너에게 시간을 줬어, 기회를 줬어
But what did you do?
그런데 당신은 무엇을 했나요?
you should know
당신은 알고 있어야
Linglong and I have different feelings.
링롱과 나는 다른 감정을 갖고 있어요
So you thought
그래서 당신은 생각했다
Is asking a woman to compensate for me considered compensation?
나를 위해 여자에게 보상을 요구하는 것이 보상으로 간주됩니까?
No, I didn't know that the envoy was Linglong.
아니요, 그 사절이 링룽인 줄은 몰랐어요
The reason for asking the big princess...
큰 공주에게 부탁하는 이유는 ‥
Do you think she's just an ordinary female envoy?
그냥 평범한 여자 사절이라고 생각하시나요?
Then you can do nothing and leave the incarnation to the Father.
그러면 당신은 아무것도 하지 않고 화신을 아버지에게 맡길 수 있습니다.
I clearly know that Hua Duguan will definitely prefer him.
Hua Duguan이 확실히 그를 선호할 것이라는 것을 분명히 알고 있습니다.
And you still did it?
그런데 아직도 해냈어?
'Cause you only feel it in your heart
왜냐하면 당신은 그것을 마음으로 느끼기 때문입니다.
The fate of a simple female envoy
단순한 여성 사절의 운명
A person like this is worthless in your eyes.
이런 사람은 당신 눈에는 가치가 없습니다.
You told me once that you would never target me again.
당신은 한 번 나에게 다시는 나를 목표로 삼지 않을 것이라고 말했습니다.
I almost believed you
난 거의 당신을 믿었어요
I would like to believe that perhaps you too may be involved in the work of our shepherd family.
어쩌면 당신도 우리 목자 가족의 일에 관여하고 있을지도 모른다고 믿고 싶습니다.
without any knowledge
아무 지식도 없이
But what happened to Linglong made me understand.
하지만 Linglong에게 일어난 일은 나를 이해하게 해줬어요
I have absolutely no choice to forgive you
나는 당신을 용서할 선택의 여지가 전혀 없습니다
Because of what your Hua family did.
너희 Hua 가족이 한 짓 때문에
People suffering in secret
비밀리에 고통받는 사람들
In addition, there are countless
그 밖에도 셀 수 없이 많은
And after all, you are also from the Hua family.
그리고 결국 당신도 Hua 가족 출신입니다.
In the end, he is still as cold and selfish as ever.
결국 그는 여전히 여전히 차갑고 이기적이다.
Since you can't see it, you can pretend not to know
안 보이니까 모른 척 해도 돼
but i
하지만 나는
no
아니요
so
그래서
This is the original intention in designing Huashen.
이것이 Huashen을 디자인하는 원래 의도입니다.
Revenge on Linglong
링롱에 대한 복수
You don't have to deal with that person.
그 사람을 상대할 필요는 없어
Then I'll make sure he gets what he deserves.
그럼 그 사람이 마땅한 대가를 치르게 해줄게
You do not take the life of a female envoy seriously.
당신은 여성 사절의 생명을 심각하게 생각하지 않습니다.
Then, the identity of me as Jong Ye-ran’s concubine?
그럼 내가 종예란의 첩이라는 정체는
Do you think you can make Hua Shen shed a layer of skin?
Hua Shen이 피부 한 겹을 벗게 할 수 있다고 생각하시나요?
This way too
이 방법으로도
Take advantage of people who love you
당신을 사랑하는 사람들을 이용하십시오
What happened using this method?
이 방법을 사용하면 어떻게 되었나요?
Are you the only person in the world allowed to bully others?
당신은 세상에서 다른 사람을 괴롭히는 것이 허용된 유일한 사람입니까?
Aren't other people allowed to resist?
다른 사람들은 저항하는 것이 허용되지 않습니까?
for me
나를 위한
As far as dealing with the Hua family
Hua 가족을 상대로 하는 한
It's clean no matter which method you use.
어떤 방법을 사용해도 깨끗합니다.
good
좋은
all right
알겠어요
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Madam, what's going on?
부인, 무슨 일이세요?
Yes or no‥
예 혹은 아니오‥
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
From now on, without my permission
앞으로는 내 허락 없이
You cannot enter Ayao's yard.
아야오의 마당에 들어갈 수 없습니다.
The best of the day...
그날의 가장 ......
If there are no obstacles
장애물이 없다면
Will your sword fall on my head?
당신의 칼이 내 머리에 떨어지겠습니까?
The answer is a resounding yes
대답은 확실히 그렇습니다
Nakaya Ake
나카야 아케
Is that jade pendant that important?
그 옥 펜던트가 그렇게 중요한가요?
When I was young I went to the temple with you, and who was the one who kept vigil?
내가 어렸을 때 당신과 함께 성전에 갔었는데, 철야를 지키던 사람은 누구였습니까?
Is it really that important?
그게 정말 그렇게 중요한가요?
you like someone
당신은 누군가를 좋아해요
Is it based on the jade pendant and memories?
옥 펜던트와 추억을 바탕으로 한 걸까요?
What are you telling me now?
지금 나한테 무슨 말을 하는 겁니까?
I want to ask ‥
묻고 싶다 ‥
Is that person a scammer?
그 사람이 사기꾼인가요?
Will everything I do from now on be wrong?
앞으로 내가 하는 일은 모두 잘못된 일이 될까?
this life
이 삶
There is no opportunity to edit or modify it.
수정하거나 수정할 기회가 없습니다.
Even if I lose my life
목숨을 잃는다고 해도
You can't even draw a sword on me
당신은 나에게 칼을 뽑을 수도 없습니다
Want to buy yourself some time to defend yourself?
자신을 방어할 시간을 벌고 싶으신가요?
You're showing weakness in front of me now
넌 지금 내 앞에서 약함을 보이고 있어
Just to soften my mood and let Hua Shen go, right?
그냥 내 기분을 부드럽게 만들고 Hua Shen을 놓아주기 위해서죠?
my uncle said so
삼촌이 그렇다고 했어
That's it
그게 다야
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
It turned out to be Qian Zhi.
Qian Zhi로 밝혀졌습니다.
How do you plan to deal with the Huashen issue?
화신(Huashen) 문제는 어떻게 처리할 계획인가요?
It all depends on your uncle.
모든 것은 삼촌에게 달려 있습니다.
uncle
삼촌
Magistrate Wang Xuan's uncle's people have not left yet.
왕현 행정관의 삼촌의 사람들은 아직 떠나지 않았습니다.
How should I answer this time?
이번에는 어떻게 대답해야 할까요?
It is recommended to press first
먼저 누르는 것이 좋습니다
yes
예
I think you have suffered serious internal injuries.
내 생각엔 당신이 심각한 내부 부상을 입은 것 같습니다.
But why do you only want Mount Jindaosan?
그런데 왜 진다오산만 원하는 걸까요?
How about giving a diagnosis?
진단을 드리는 것은 어떨까요?
There is no need as long as the golden sword flies
필요없어 황금검이 흩날리는 한
- Please help me quickly. - Looks like it's in good condition here.
- 빨리 도와주세요. - 여기 상태는 괜찮은 것 같군요.
No wounds
상처도 없고
Why do you want Jin Daosan to heal your trauma?
왜 Jin Daosan이 트라우마를 치료하기를 원하십니까?
Did you find that?
그거 찾았 어?
I'm looking for you‥
내가 찾고 있어요‥
I found it... Where is the wound?
찾았어요‥상처는 어디에 있나요?
Come on, let me bandage you.
자, 내가 붕대를 감아줄게
Why are you so anxious?
왜 그렇게 불안해?
Doctor, do you have any golden sword powder?
박사님, 황금검 가루 있나요?
What happened at home today?
오늘 집에서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Who is injured?
부상당한 사람은 누구입니까?
Why is everyone asking for Jindaosan?
왜 다들 진다오산을 요구하는 걸까요?
hurry up, please. I need it urgently.
서둘러 주세요. 급히 필요해요.
continued
계속되는
Thanks for watching
시청 해주셔서 감사합니다